JESUS GARCIA RAMIREZ

Machine Learning Engineer

📞 +34 665444632 🛘 @ jgarciaramirezai@gmail.com 🔣 linkedin.com/in/jesusgarciaramirez 🕏 github.com/jeux19 Leuven

EDUCATION

Advanced Master's in Artificial Intelligence

KU Leuven

益 2020

- Graduated Magna Cum Laude
- Thesis: Efficient analysis of mobile eye tracker data using deep learning

Erasmus exchange

KU Leuven

2019 - 2020

B.Sc. in Industrial Engineering

University of Seville

2015 - 2019

· Major in Systems Control

SKILLS

Python	Pytorch	Pai	ndas
Scikit-Learn OpenCV			Matlab
NumPy	SciPy	Git	CNNs
Computer Vision		Control Systems	

STRENGTHS



Quick Learner

Seamless project transitions during PhD, leading Brain-Machine Interface development and developing CNN models for precise neuron responses predictions



Pro-Active

Throughout my PhD, I consistently took initiative to find solutions to novel research questions



Effective Communication

Presented research outcomes in interdisciplinary teams, creating interactive visualizations and presenting at international conferences

SUMMARY

Leveraging a passion for learning and research, I excel in translating complex challenges into practical machine learning solutions. Committed to continuous personal and professional growth, drawing inspiration from the discipline and focus cultivated through my passion for running.

EXPERIENCE

PhD Candidate

KU Leuven

01/2022 - Present

- · Developed CNN-based encoding models for predicting individual neuron responses to naturalistic images recorded from visual cortex of epileptic patients
- Successfully developed and fine-tuned CNN-based encoding models, explaining 80% of the explainable **variance** within the neural responses
- Created an **interactive visualization** to showcase the relationship between the presented images and the neural response patterns within the latent space of trained models by using **UMAP** to reduce the latent space dimensionality
- Tech stack: Python, PyTorch, Scikit-Learn, OpenCV, SciPy, NumPy, Bokeh

Research Engineer

KU Leuven

= 12/2020 - 01/2022

- Led the development of a cutting-edge **decoding pipeline** for mapping intended arm movements to 3D simulated robot trajectories using macaque neural data
- Implemented a novel nonlinear extension of Kalman filter models, achieving over 90% of decoding success rate with order of us inference latency
- Developed an online retraining procedure, resulting in a substantial 92% reduction in the amount of data required to train the decoding models
- Tech stack: Python, Pandas, Scikit-Learn, SciPy, Matlab, NumPy

PROJECTS

Efficient analysis of mobile eye tracker data using Deep Learning

= 2019 - 2020

https://github.com/gestaltrevision/tracking-vermeersch

- Developed an automatic labelling tool to streamline the analysis of mobile eye-tracking recordings during an art exhibition
- Achieved over 90% accuracy in predicting participant's observed item by fine-tuning the state-of-the-art video classification model, using a manually curated 10k-sample dataset
- Adapted and trained ResNet based architectures using recorded accelerometer, gaze, and gyroscope data for behaviour prediction, attaining over 70% accuracy
- Tech stack: Python, OpenCV, Pandas, PyTorch, SciPy

CONFERENCE PROCEEDINGS

Single neuron signatures of spatial attention in the human lateral occipital complex

Society for Neuroscience

Comparing reach direction decoding in macaque ventral premotor, dorsal premotor and primary motor cortex

Neural Control of Movement

Single unit correlates of visual reasoning in the human lateral occipital complex

Society for Neuroscience

m 11/2022

San Diego, USA

Object decoding with spatial attention in the human lateral occipital complex

Federation of European Neuroscience Societies

m 07/2022

Paris, France

Decoding reaching direction from macaque dorsal and ventral premotor and primary cortex

Society for Neuroscience